Martha Graham Collection
Music Division, Library of Congress
- Correspondence (Box 229-238; 377-387; 398)
  The Correspondence series in the Martha Graham Collection is divided into two sections. The first covers the day-to-day activities of the Martha Graham Center of Contemporary Dance and the Martha Graham School. The letters (some carbon copies and xeroxes), memoranda, telefaxes, and telegrams are arranged chronologically by year. The correspondence is not inclusive, but covers activities from 1930 to 1996, with the majority of items from the 1980s and 1990s. The series also contains consignments, contracts, letters of agreement, promissory notes, and licenses, as well as correspondence, agendas, and member lists for the Martha Graham Center of Contemporary Dance Board of Trustees and legal documents relating to the day-to-day activities of the Center. The second section consists of correspondence to and from Martha Graham that was unrestricted in 2008. Finally there are twelve containers of correspondence determined to be of a personal nature that are currently restricted.
  The first section is arranged chronologically by year. The second section is arranged alphabetically by name.
  - Correspondence Dealing with Activities of the Martha Graham Center of Contemporary Dance and the Martha Graham School (Box 229-238)
    - Letters, Memoranda, Telefaxes, and Telegrams (Box 229-236)
      - 1930; 1931; 1937; 1940; 1942; 1944; 1945; 1946 (Box-folder 229/1)
      - 1947; 1948; 1949 (Box-folder 229/2)
      - 1950 (Box-folder 229/3)
      - 1951 (Box-folder 229/4-5)
      - 1952 (Box-folder 229/6)
      - 1953 (Box-folder 229/7)
      - 1954; 1955; 1956 (Box-folder 230/1)
      - 1957; 1958 (Box-folder 230/2)
      - 1960; 1962; 1963; 1965; 1968; 1969 (Box-folder 230/3)
      - 1970 (Box-folder 230/4)
      - 1971 (Box-folder 230/5-8)
      - 1972 (Box-folder 230/9)
      - 1973 (Box-folder 231/1-3)
      - 1974 (Box-folder 231/4-5)
      - 1975; 1976; 1977; 1979 (Box-folder 231/6)
      - 1980; 1981; 1982; 1983 (Box-folder 231/7)
      - 1984; 1985 (Box-folder 231/8)
      - 1986 (Box-folder 232/1)
      - 1987 (Box-folder 232/2)
      - 1988 (Box-folder 232/3-15)
      - 1989 (Box-folder 233/1-3)
      - 1990 (Box-folder 233/4-7)
      - 1991 (Box-folder 233/8-11)
      - 1993 (Box-folder 234/1-4)
      - 1994 (Box-folder 234/5-6)
      - 1995 (Box-folder 234/7-9)
      - 1995 (Box-folder 235/1-6)
      - 1996 (Box-folder 235/7-8)
      - 1996 (Box-folder 236/1-2)
      - Undated items; letter fragments; unknown senders (Box-folder 236/3-4)
      - Fan mail; cards and invitations (Box-folder 236/5-7)
    - Consignments, Contracts, Letters of Agreement, Promissory Notes, and Licenses (Box 237)
      - American National Theatre and Academy, 1948 Isadora Bennett, 1948 Juilliard School of Music, 1952 Nathan Kroll, 1956 Martha Graham Foundation for Contemporary Dance, Inc., 1966 (Box-folder 237/1)
      - Adams Productions, 1970 Brooklyn College of CUNY (Shaw Concerts), 1970 State University of New York, Binghamton, 1970 Kritas Productions, Athens, 1971 New York State Council on the Arts, 1972 Alvin Theatre, 1973 Takako Asakawa, 1973 Feller Scenery Studios, 1973 Four Star Stage Lighting, 1973 Lake Placid Association, 1973 Merlin Group, Ltd., 1973 National Public Television, 1973-1975 Dance Notation Bureau, Inc., [197-?] C.F. Peters Corporation, 1973 David Hatch Walker, 1973 (Box-folder 237/2)
      - Columbia Artists, 1974 Department of State, 1974 Far East Conference, 1974 Feller Scenery Studios, Inc., 1974 Kazuko Hillyer International, Inc., 1974 Nippon Cultural Centre, 1974 Corporation for Public Broadcasting, 1975 Educational Broadcasting Corporation, 1976 Pace University/Schimel Center for the Arts, 1979 (Box-folder 237/3)
      - Alison Dodd, 1980 55th Street Dance Theater Foundation, 1982 “A Diamond for Martha” auction agreement, 1986 WNET/Thirteen, 1988 Art Planning, 1989 Doubleday, 1989 Educational Broadcasting Corporation, 1989 National Corporate Fund for Dance, Inc., 1989 Sotheby’s, 1989 Paul Szilard Productions, Inc., 1989 WNET/Thirteen, 1989 (Box-folder 237/4)
      - Chase Manhattan Bank, 1990 Spain ’92 Foundation, 1990 (2) Creative Artists Agency, Inc., 1991 L’Opera de Paris, 1991 Carl Fischer, 1992 City Center, 1992 Gedeon Saul, 1992 Juilliard School, 1992 Marymount Manhattan College, 1992 (Box-folder 237/5)
      - Chase Manhattan Bank, 1993 Marymount Manhattan College, 1993 North American Watch, 1993 Isamu Noguchi Foundation, 1995 PaceWildenstein, 1996 WNET/Thirteen, 1996 (2) Contract Proposal for Ballet Companies, United Scenic Artists, Local 829, undated Release, Dance in America, undated Television Espanola, S.A., undated (Box-folder 237/6)
      - Contract fragments (1st or 1st and 2nd pages), undated; 1973; 1975; 1990; 1991 (Box-folder 237/7)
    - Correspondence and Materials Related to the Board of Trustees and Legal Documents, 1968-1988 (Box 238)
      - Minutes, Board of Trustees (Box-folder 238/1)
      - Agendas, Board of Trustees (Box-folder 238/2)
      - Lists of members, Board of Trustees (Box-folder 238/3)
      - Legal documents: United States Department of Justice, Notice of Approval or Extension of Nonimmigrant Visa Petition, 1988 Department of Treasury non-509 (a) determination, 1975 Bylaws of the Martha Graham School of Contemporary Dance, Inc., undated Certification of Incorporation, Martha Graham School of Contemporary Dance; Certificate of Change of Name of Martha Graham Foundation for Contemporary Dance to Martha Graham Center of Contemporary Dance, 1968 Consent of Sole Surviving Member/Incorporator, 1987 (Box-folder 238/4)
  - Unrestricted Correspondence (Box 398)
    - To Martha Graham (Box 398)
      - Armstrong (US Ambassador) (Box-folder 398/1)
      - Baer, Joseph (Box-folder 398/2)
      - Baity, Elizabeth Chesley (Box-folder 398/3)
      - Barton, Craig (Box-folder 398/4)
      - Batchelder, William H. (Box-folder 398/5)
      - Bentley, Eric (Box-folder 398/6)
      - Brennecke, Tom (to and from) (Box-folder 398/7)
      - Buchanan, Wiley T. [US Ambassador to Austria, 1975-1977] (Box-folder 398/8)
      - Carson, Mrs. G. Prentice (Box-folder 398/9)
      - Chavda, Shiavax (Box-folder 398/10)
      - Council of Fashion Designers (Box-folder 398/11)
      - Curtis, Donald (Church of Religious Science) (Box-folder 398/12)
      - Dance News Invitation-Chamié, Tatiana (Box-folder 398/13)
      - Davis, I. (Box-folder 398/14)
      - Fine, Michael [Cunningham Dance Foundation] (Box-folder 398/15)
      - Fischer, Barry (Box-folder 398/16)
      - Fonteyn, Margot (Box-folder 398/17)
      - Ford, Betty (Box-folder 398/18)
      - Furse, Anna (Box-folder 398/19)
      - Goldberg, H. (Box-folder 398/20)
      - Goodkind, Louis W. (Box-folder 398/21)
      - Graham Dance Company (card to Martha) (Box-folder 398/22)
      - Graham, Martha (solicitations) (Box-folder 398/23)
      - Graham School (Box-folder 398/24)
      - Hare, Raymond (US Ambassador to Turkey, 1961-1965) (Box-folder 398/25)
      - Harkness, Mrs. William H. (Box-folder 398/26)
      - Hendelson, Margaret (Box-folder 398/27)
      - Highet, Helen (Box-folder 398/28)
      - Hindemith, Paul (assistant to) (Box-folder 398/29)
      - Hoffman, May Foke (Box-folder 398/30)
      - Hovhaness, Alan (Box-folder 398/31)
      - Jackson, David (Box-folder 398/32)
      - Johns, Jasper (from Martha Graham) (Box-folder 398/33)
      - Jones, Lewis (Box-folder 398/34)
      - Kanda, Akiko (Box-folder 398/35)
      - Kawakami, Takako (Box-folder 398/36)
      - Kenedy, Hailou (Box-folder 398/37)
      - Kikuchi, Yuriko (Box-folder 398/38)
      - Kirstein, Lincoln (Box-folder 398/39)
      - Kuypens, John M. (Box-folder 398/40)
      - Lalaounis, Ilias (Box-folder 398/41)
      - Leona, Margaret (Box-folder 398/42)
      - Leonard, Fox, Ltd. [rare books] (Box-folder 398/43)
      - Liebenberg, Jean (Box-folder 398/44)
      - MacArthur, Gray [New York State Council on the Arts] (Box-folder 398/45)
      - Masrty-Ané, C. (Box-folder 398/46)
      - Masani, Mrs. M. R. (Box-folder 398/47)
      - McBean, Angus (Box-folder 398/48)
      - McCormick, K.D. (Box-folder 398/49)
      - Menotti, Gian Carlo (Box-folder 398/50)
      - Merola, James (Box-folder 398/51)
      - Morgan, Barbara (Box-folder 398/52)
      - Moschopoulos, Paris (Box-folder 398/53)
      - Newhouse, Mitzi (Box-folder 398/54)
      - Ohba, Sab. (Box-folder 398/55)
      - Onassis, Jackie (Box-folder 398/56)
      - Parsons, J. Graham [US Ambassador to Stockholm 1961-1965] (Box-folder 398/57)
      - Price, Richard (Box-folder 398/58)
      - Ralph M. Chait Gallery (Box-folder 398/59)
      - Robbins, Jerome (Box-folder 398/60)
      - Rothschild, Bethsabee de (Box-folder 398/61)
      - Shawn, Ted (Box-folder 398/62)
      - St. Denis, Ruth (Box-folder 398/63)
      - Taggard, Genevieve (Box-folder 398/64)
      - Taylor, Conni (Box-folder 398/65)
      - Tcherepnin, Ming & Alexander (Box-folder 398/66)
      - Thompson, Daryl (Box-folder 398/67)
      - Thomson, Virgil (Box-folder 398/68)
      - Tucker, John A. (Box-folder 398/69)
      - Tully, Alice (Box-folder 398/70)
      - Welch, Mary (Box-folder 398/71)
      - Wigman, Mary (Box-folder 398/72)
      - Wilson, Dwight (Box-folder 398/73)
      - Windhausen, Wolfgang (Box-folder 398/74)
      - Xu, Han [Ambassador from People’s Republic of China to US 1985-1989] (Box-folder 398/75)
      - Zemach, Benjamin [University of Judaism] (Box-folder 398/76)
      - Unidentified (Box-folder 398/77)
    - From Martha Graham (Box 398)
      - Barber, Samuel (Box-folder 398/78)
      - Dello Joio, Norman (Box-folder 398/79)
      - De Mille, Agnes (Box-folder 398/80)
      - Protas, Ron (Box-folder 398/81)
      - Rabin, Arnold (Box-folder 398/82)
  - Restricted Correspondence (Box 377-387)
- Production Elements (Box 203-204)
  The Production Elements series consists of information relating to the New York City season performances and touring, including hanging plots, light plots and light cue tracks, call sheets, and condition reports. The lighting, set, and costume designers include Jean Rosenthal, Rouben Ter-Arutunian, Isamu Noguchi, Donna Karan, Beverly Emmons, Jennifer Tipton, and Thomas Skelton.
  - Equipment lists: Fall tour, 1970 Blossom Festival, undated (Box-folder 203/1)
  - Condition reports, 1973, 1991 (Box-folder 203/2)
  - Orchestra requirements, undated (Box-folder 203/3)
  - Shipments: London, 1963 European tour, 1967 Mexico City, 1968 (Box-folder 203/4)
  - Hanging plots: Mark Hellinger Theatre, New York City, 1967 Saville Theatre, London, 1967 Unidentified, undated (Box-folder 203/5)
  - Lighting cues (Box-folder 203/6)
  - Performance venue technical sheets (Box-folder 203/7)
  - Light and hanging plots for 1974 tour, Lighting by Jean Rosenthal and William H. Batchelder. (Box-folder 203/8)
  - Hanging plot, lighting plot, and main scaffold in elevation for Episodes (Box-folder 203/9)
  - Light plot by Jean Rosenthal for the Long Island Festival, 1967 (Box-folder 203/10)
  - Light plot, Blossom Festival, undated (Box-folder 203/11)
  - Light plot by Jean Rosenthal for North American tour, 1989 (Box-folder 203/12)
  - Light plot, Israel tour, 1958 (Box-folder 203/13)
  - Light cue track for Part Real – Part Dream, 1968 (Box-folder 203/14)
  - Light cue track for Cortege of Eagles, [1967?] (Box-folder 203/15)
  - Light plot by Jean Rosenthal for 1960 New York City season, 54th Street Theatre (Box-folder 203/16)
  - Light plot by Thomas Skelton for the American Dance Festival, 1961 (Box-folder 203/17)
  - Section plot by Thomas Skelton for the American Dance Festival, 1962 (Box-folder 203/18)
  - Board hookup, 1962 Broadway season, 54th Street Theatre (Box-folder 203/19)
  - Light plot and hanging plot, New York City Center season, 1969 (Box-folder 203/20)
  - Light plot, 54th Street Theatre, 1968 (Box-folder 203/21)
  - Light plot by lighting designers: Beverly Emmons, Jean Rosenthal, Jennifer Tipton, Thomas Skelton for the American Dance Festival, Connecticut College, 1967 (Box-folder 203/22)
  - Hanging, stage, and auditorium sections for Edinburgh International Festival and photographs of the venues (Box-folder 203/23)
  - Donna Karan costume designs (Box-folder 203/24)
  - Sketches for set design by Isamu Noguchi (Box-folder 203/25)
  - Section light plot (preliminary plot), American Dance Festival, Connecticut College, 1967 (Box-folder 204/1)
  - Elevation, hanging plot, and light plot from 1960 New York City season, 54th Street Theatre, Lighting by Jean Rosenthal, revised 1961. (Box-folder 204/2)
  - 1963 New York City season, Lunt Fontanne Theatre light plot by Jean Rosenthal; Tormenters (Box-folder 204/3)
  - Architects drawings for Space Theater for Dance and Noguchi sets (architects: Isamu Noguchi/Fuller & Sadao, Inc.), 1975 (Box-folder 204/4)
  - Touring light and hanging plots, 1974, Lighting by Jean Rosenthal and William H. Batchelder. (Box-folder 204/5)
  - Light and hanging plots, 1970 Fall tour, Lighting by Jean Rosenthal, William H. Batchelder, and H.P. Poindexter. (Box-folder 204/6)
  - Elevation, Adelphi Theatre, New York City, 1958-1961 (Box-folder 204/7)
  - From One More Gaudy Night: ground plan and elevation, design by Jean Rosenthal; stool and moon set plans; elevations and boat (Box-folder 204/8)
  - From Phaedra, Broadway 1962/Connecticut College 1962, cue sheet with scenery, set pieces, props (Box-folder 204/9)
  - From Night Journey, 54th Street Theatre, New York City 1960, cue sheet (Box-folder 204/10)
  - Call sheet (cast and crew), 1961 April 10 (Box-folder 204/11)
  - Basic touring light and hanging plots, 1970 (revised 1973), Lighting designs by Jean Rosenthal and William H. Batchelder. (Box-folder 204/12)
  - Visionary recital for Martha Graham, 1961 March 8; Ground plan, design by Rouben Ter-Arutunian (Box-folder 204/13)
  - Louis Horst memorial, American Dance Festival, light plots, 1964 (Box-folder 204/14)
  - House fronts and Cyc Border; Graham draperies and torms, Israel and Europe, 1962, Jean Rosenthal, designer. (Box-folder 204/15)
  - Empire Theater, Edinburgh, electric layout, 1963 (Box-folder 204/16)
  - Martha Graham 1962 European tour, equipment layout (Box-folder 204/17)
  - 1966 U.S. tour, light plot, lighting by Jean Rosenthal; ground plan (Box-folder 204/18)
  - Hartwell Theatre, lighting and rigging (Box-folder 204/19)
  - Crate list and shipping lists (Box-folder 204/20)
  - Unidentified production items (Box-folder 204/21)
  - List of Noguchi sets and props (Box-folder 204/22)
- Special Projects (Box 307)
  The Special Projects series consists of materials that relate to activities of the Martha Graham Center of Contemporary Dance between 1973 and 1992. It contains letters, memoranda, faxes, telegrams, and other items (notes, budgets, itineraries) for a number of ventures, including the 1973 summer Lake Placid, New York residency; the 1993 patrons tour to Spain; the Marymount Choreographers Project, 1988 and 1992; and special projects with sculptor Isamu Noguchi from 1982 to 1985.
  Arranged by project.
  - MGCCD summer 1973 Lake Placid, New York residency (Box-folder 307/1)
  - MGCCD patrons tour to Spain, 1993 (Box-folder 307/2)
  - MGCCD patrons tour to Spain, 1993 (Box-folder 307/3)
  - MGCCD art planning, Rimini, Italy, 1988-1990 (Box-folder 307/4)
  - MGCCD 1990 Spain ’92 Foundation (Box-folder 307/5)
  - MGCCD Marymount Choreographers Project, 1988 (Box-folder 307/6)
  - MGCCD Marymount Choreographers Project, 1992 (Box-folder 307/7)
  - MGCCD Noguchi projects, 1982-1985 (Box-folder 307/8)
  - MGCCD Noguchi projects, 1982-1985 (Box-folder 307/9)
  - MGCCD Noguchi collaboration, 1985 (Box-folder 307/10)
- Writings by and about Martha Graham (Box 224-228; 306)
  The series Writings by and about Martha Graham consists of literary notes by Martha Graham or others for various choreographic works; articles and speeches by Martha Graham; interviews; articles about Martha Graham; poems and miscellaneous writings sent to Graham or contained in her papers, and fragments of literary works by and for Graham.
  Organized by major heading (“Literary Notes,” for example) and arranged alphabetically by author or by choreographic work therein. In some cases, folders are organized chronologically.
  - Literary Notes (Box 224)
    Literary notes by Martha Graham for choreographic works (some fragments); literary notes by others for choreographic works.
    - Alcestis (Box-folder 224/1)
    - American Document (Box-folder 224/2)
    - Appalachian Spring (Box-folder 224/3)
    - Canticle for Innocent Comedians (Box-folder 224/4)
    - Clytemnestra (Box-folder 224/5)
    - Every Soul is a Circus (Box-folder 224/6)
    - Heloise and Abelard (Box-folder 224/7)
    - Holy Jungle (Box-folder 224/8)
    - I Salute My Love (Box-folder 224/9)
    - Lucifer (Box-folder 224/10)
    - Punch and the Judy (Box-folder 224/11)
    - Salem Shore (choreographic notes by Terese Capucilli and Carol Fried) (Box-folder 224/12)
    - Scarlet Letter (Box-folder 224/13)
    - Stone of Destiny (Box-folder 224/14)
    - Witch of Endor (Box-folder 224/15)
    - “Valley of Vision,” “Nautilus,” “The Lady of the Labyrinth” (notes by Robert Starer); Diversion of Angels (notes by B.B.) (Box-folder 224/16)
    - Unidentified fragments of literary notes for choreographic works; miscellaneous writings, (15 items) (Box-folder 224/17)
  - Articles and Speeches by Martha Graham (Box 224)
    - “John Martin Remembered,” in Ballet Review, Spring 1988 “Relates to After Tudor,” n.d. “Introduction,” draft, 1963 February 15 “A Tribute to Margot Fonteyn,” 1990 (Box-folder 224/18)
  - Writings about Martha Graham (Box 225-226)
    Poems, writings, and scripts sent to Graham or contained in her papers (authors identified).
    - Angelou, Maya. Still I Rise. Apostolos-Cappadona, Diane. “The Ritual of Sculpture: Isamu Noguchi’s ‘From Behind Inner Seeking: Síva’s Dance,” 1984. Armitage, Merle. “Modern Dance,” (section) 1935. Armitage, Merle. “Modern Dance,” (section in French), n.d. Armitage, Merle, et al. “Big Chief of the Southwest.” (shooting script), n.d. (Box-folder 225/1)
    - Ballard, Adele, M. “Midnight at June Second,” n.d. Barnhardt, Harry. Script for unnamed ballet, n.d. Berg, Paul. “Martha Graham’s Dancers” in St. Louis Post-Dispatch, Sunday, 1970 October 18. Berlitt, Ben. “Soundstage,” 1945. Blofeld, John. [lacks title and date] Buckwalter, John. “Byzantine Eyes,” n.d. Buckwalter, John. “A Psalm of Joy,” 1963. (Box-folder 225/2)
    - Cahn, Sammy. “His Way.” Candee, Helen Churchill. “Ankor, the Magnificant,” n.d. Caras, Roger. Quotes from “The Private Lives of Animals,” n.d. Code, Grant. “Prologue,” n.d. Cook, Helen Fetter. “Enchanted Land,” 1944. (Box-folder 225/3)
    - De LaRosa, L. “Production by Martha Graham,” 1987. De Mille, Agnes. No title, n.d. Devi, Rukmini. Chapter for a book, Where Theosophy and Science Meet, by Prof. D.D. Kanga, n.d. (Box-folder 225/4)
    - Eisner, Igor. “Evocation de Martha Graham,” 1991. Engle, Paul. “Door,” n.d. Engle, Paul. “Variations,” n.d. (Box-folder 225/5)
    - Fowlie, Wallace. “Martha Graham as Hérodiade,” n.d. Fowlie, Wallace. “Martha Graham comme Hérodiade,” n.d. (Box-folder 225/6)
    - Gable, Maureen Clark. “Gone With Noelle,” n.d. Gale, Joseph. “The First Lady of Modern American Dance,” in Newark Sunday News, 1970 September 27. Gold, Ronald. “From Pungent Image to Vivid Life,” in Dance Magazine, 1969 May. Goodman, Saul. “Takako Asakawa,” in Dance Magazine, 1971 January. Goodman, Saul. “Rahamin Ron,” in Dance Magazine, 1971 February. Grendysa, Peter. “The Case of the Disappearing Composer,” n.d. (Box-folder 225/7)
    - Hawwend (?), Richard. “Scenario for Abstract Ballet on the Story of Solomon – for Martha Graham,” 1931. Hodes, Stuart. “Review of Blood Memory,” in Ballet Review, 1991. Horosko, Marian. “Frontier of the Mind: Martha Graham at 95,” in Dance Magazine, 1989 May. Howard, Robin. Obituary in Ballet Review, 1989. Hull, William D. “On Martha Graham’s visit to Ceylon,” n.d. (Box-folder 225/8)
    - Ignatin, Irving. “New Theatre,” 1935 December. (Box-folder 225/9)
    - Jacobsohn, Helmuth. “The World-Weary Man and his Soul,” 1952. Jellinghaus, Fritz. [no title,] 1981. (Box-folder 225/10)
    - Kaplan, Howard. “Simple Gifts,” 1987. Kostopoulos, Carmela. “For Martha Graham on her 90th Birthday,” n.d. Kulick, Jonathan, et al. “A True Story for Martha Graham,” n.d. (Box-folder 225/11)
    - Larsson, Raymond E.F. “Good Friday Music,” n.d. Leatherman, LeRoy. [“A Note on Martha Graham’s Symbolism”], n.d. Leatherman, LeRoy. “Homage to the Secret-Bearer,” in The Sewanee Review, vol. LXXII, No. 2, April-June 1964. Legisos, Gloria M. “Danza Contemporanea Iniciacion al Aprendizaje de la Tecnica Graham,” Santiago, Chile, 1977 (Box-folder 225/12)
    - March, William. “The Bad Seed,” n.d. Marchal, Sappho. “Danses Cambodgiennes,” Saigon, MCMXXVI. Martin, John. [quotation in French], n.d. Martin, John. “A Classic,” n.d. Mason, Francis. “Martha Graham Dance Company,” n.d. McDonagh, Don. “Modern Dance Chronicle,” in The Hudson Review, vol XXII, no. 2, Summer 1969. Meursinge, B. “The Tree of Great Sorrow,” n.d. Mishima, Yukio. “The Damask Drum,” in Five Modern Nō Plays, 1957. Moe, Henry Allen. Remarks for Martha Graham convocation, Aspen Institute for Humanistic Studies, 1965. Acceptance speech for Aspen Award by Martha Graham. Myers, L.H. “The/Root and the/Flower,” n.d. (Box-folder 225/13)
    - Nauman, Hilda. “Around Eastern Connecticut,” n.d. Neal, Josie. “Modern Dance: The American Experience,” 1989. (Box-folder 225/14)
    - Patterson, Daniel W. “Early Shaker Spirituals,” 1976. Pena, Jose Z de la. “The Four Apparitions of the Blessed Virgin of Guadalupe,” n.d. Perse, Saint-John. “Anabasis, “ n.d. Phelps, Mary. “Advertisement,” 1938. (Box-folder 226/1)
    - Rudhyar, D. “Martha Graham’s Utterances Reveal a New Dance Rhythm,” n.d. (Box-folder 226/2)
    - Sabin, Robert. “The Evolution of Martha Graham’s Dance Technique,” n.d. Saint Victor, Hugh de. “Conversation Concerning the Wedding Gift of the Soul (summary)” Barbara Hanna, translator. Sark. “A Creative Companion,” n.d. Sherman, Jane and Norton Owen. “Martha Graham and Ted Shawn,” in Dance Magazine, 1995. Shirley, Wayne. A Ballet for Martha. Library of Congress. [Soars, Janet]. “Interview with [Christena Schlundt] on Ruth St. Denis,” in Dance Chronicle, n.d. Smith, Arthur Galusha. “Indian,” n.d. Smith, Cecil. “The Maze of the Heart,” in Theatre Arts, May 1947. Stav, Arie. “The Dance in Israel,” in Hadassah Magazine, Hartford, Connecticut, February 1971. Stodelle, Ernestine. “The View from Vermont,” chapter 7 from Deep Song: The Dance Story of Martha Graham, 1983. Sweeney, James Johnson. “Martha Graham,” n.d. [Synge, John Millinton]. Riders to the Sea, 1904. (Box-folder 226/3)
    - Richman, Robert. “Erick Hawkins,” n.d. Rothschild, Bethsabee de. Extract from La Danse Artistique aux USA, 1949. (Box-folder 226/4)
    - Taylor, Harold. Remarks by president of Sarah Lawrence College at Dance Magazine Awards ceremony, 1958. Terry, Walter. “Martha Graham’s Repertory,” n.d. Tracy, Robert. “Noguchi: Collaborating with Graham,” in Ballet Review, 9, Winter 1986 Tracy, Robert. “Artist’s Dialogue: Isamu Noguchi,” n.d. (Box-folder 226/5)
    - Ulrich, Celeste. “Martha Graham,” n.d. (Box-folder 226/6)
    - Weigle, Marta. “The Penitentes of the Southwest,” n.d. Weinberg, Nathan. “Horses, Machines and Dancers,” n.d. Williams, Peter and Clive Barnes. “Two Looks at Lighting: Martha Graham in Edinburgh and London,” in Dance and Dancers, 1963. Winters, Pamela. “An Introduction to Sacred Dance,” 1988. Wolfe, Katharine A. “Martha Graham,” n.d. (Box-folder 226/7)
  - Interviews (Box 226)